Jason Lee

Senior Principal Software Engineer at Oracle jason@steeplesoft.com | https://jasondl.ee

Summary

Solutions-oriented enterprise developer with over 21 years of broad-based, enterprise development. Proven ability to handle all stages of the SDLC, from requirements gathering and systems and database design, to implementation, deployment and support. Love to teach/mentor, and always eager to learn and push technologies to their limits to meet customer needs.

Languages: Java, C/C++, Kotlin, JavaScript, Python, PHP, Delphi

Tools: Jakarta EE, Spring, AngularJS, JUnit, TestNG, Selenium, Git, SVN

Mobile Development: Android

Experience

NetSuite / Oracle

October 2014 - Present

Senior Principal Software Engineer

I act as tribe architect for Oracle's NetSuite e-commerce solution. We build a modern, user-friendly frontend that allow our customers, e-shop owners, to more easily manage and update their shopping sites. Our React-based frontend works in concert with our JAX-RS-based backend to provide a more pleasant and efficient interface to an extremely powerful -- and complex -- commerce and ERP system that is regularly featured at trade shows and loved by our customers.

- Responsible for interacting with product management and other stakeholders to determine the technical requirements for a feature, preparing prototypes and/ or high-level implementation plans, and working with the implementing team to help deliver the feature
- Work with other developers across the organization to help vet architectural designs and directions, as well as working with other developers in my own group to ensure that our designs are compatible with the overall direction of the organization.
- Communicate with local team about new capabilities of the system, new libraries/tools available to use, as well as industry changes and trends that might be helpful or interesting to the team.
- As needed, interact with customers and the support organization to determine the cause of and solution for more difficult issues.

Cub Tracker

April 2011 - February 2017

Founder/Developer

Designed and implemented an Android application to assist parents and leaders in tracking the progress of Cub Scouts.

- Maintain user community to offer support and solicit application enhancement requests
- Over 10,000 downloads with a current install base of almost 4,000 users

Principal Member of Technical Staff

Designed and implemented both GUI and RESTful administration interfaces for the GlassFish and Weblogic application servers.

- Continued work on GlassFish under Oracle's stewardship
- Helped migrate REST API generation framework from GlassFish to Weblogic Server
- Contributed to the maintenance and development of the Weblogic Server administration console

Sun Microsystems

July 2008 - February 2010

Senior Java Developer

Designed and implemented both GUI and RESTful administration interfaces for the GlassFish application server. Served on JavaServer Faces 2.0 Expert Group.

- Improved user experience by modernizing the GlassFish Administration Console, integrating legacy JSF-based framework with current (ajax-enabled) standards, reducing page load times from several seconds to an average of 0.5 seconds.
- Regularly interacted with open source community handling bugs, feature requests, and general support
- Provided stable, consistent REST interface for internal and external customers
- Implemented plugin architecture for the REST interface, allowing internal and external customers to provide their own plugins based on individual needs
- Increased product reliability by designing and developing a testing framework to prevent feature loss and bug regression

Objectstream, Inc. (subcontractor for FAA)

May 2007 - July 2008

Software Architect

Worked with team of business analysts and Subject Matter Experts to design a training tracking system for the Federal Aviation Administration's Air Traffic Organization.

- Met with Subject Matter Experts to help determine functionality of system
- Developed and delivered final architectural proposal to steering committee
- Developed proof-of-concept implementations for architecturally interesting parts of the system.

International Environmental Corporation

January 2005 - May 2007

Senior Software Engineer

Designed, implemented, and supported systems to support in-house customers

- Increased reliability, availability and stability of backend database by migrating from MySQL 4 to PostgreSQL 8
- Increased application reliability by implementing unit and functional testing framework
- Made systems more predictable and easier to maintain by standardizing on a few, core technologies
- Mentored and trained teammates on new or unfamiliar technologies

Supported store back office systems to allow for sales/time reporting, etc, as well as integrating point of sales systems with iSeries backend

- Decreased downtime for stores' back office system by replacing aging AIX server with fault-tolerant Linux-based systems
- Improved end-user experience with back office system by delivering frequent bug and stability fixes to 300+ remote stores
- Insured sales were smooth and efficient by monitoring and maintaining the credit and gift card networks

Medtech / Red River Solutions

July 1998 - July 2001

Programmer/Analyst, Front-end Team Lead

Designed, implemented, and supported systems to facilitate the medical records retrieval process for our call centers

- Help design and implement distributed workflow engine that powered the business
- Led a small team of front-end developers, writing both Java- and C++-based applications
- Mentored and managed junior developers
- Simplified and sped up end-user application development process by designing an application framework that rested on top of the C++Builder GUI code
- Improved product quality by installing and maintaining a bug tracking system
- Maintained local area network for the Tulsa-based development office

Wal-Mart June 1997 - June 1998

Programmer/Analyst

Developed systems to aid the logistics management teams

- Helped design and develop an extension to the decision support system for the Logistics department
- Saved the company over \$168 million dollars by implementing a system to locate and identify inventory that had been sitting in the distribution centers for too long

Education

Oklahoma Baptist University

B.S., Computer Science · (1993 – 1997)